#### Contact

214-577-4278 (Mobile) j91branson@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/j91branson (LinkedIn)

www.jbranson.com (Portfolio) icodemag.com (Blog)

### Top Skills

JavaScript HTML

CSS

### Languages

English

# Joshua Branson

Web Developer | Writer @ iC0dE Magazine Dallas, Texas

## Summary

I got into coding to get into a career I could enjoy and excel at; I started off learning some on my own and then found a Code Camp at SMU. I enjoyed coding right away, as I got further involved I met the struggles and frustrations like all coders. I pushed through the challenges I faced and found that while frustrating every time I figured out a tough problem my skills became better. After learning more and more I enjoy coding a little more each day; and look forward to a rewarding career.

The thing that helps me in this field is my previous experience in the security field; it has made me more able to handle stressful situations and push through long hours of work. I think the other thing I get from this experience is the ability to interact with other people and teach people. I was a field training officer and then an assistant manager; so I understand teaching people and can be a good leader.

I guess the approach I take to work is to be laid back and productive; work should be fun and still a productive environment. Humor can make a great de-stresser and the more co-workers get along the more productive the team is. Other than that I'm just your basic nerd; fitting the coding stereotype.

## Experience

Integrated Controls Incorporated
Technician
December 2017 - Present
Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Install/ Repair Access Control and Camera systems.

PARMOR CONTRACTORS LIMITED

Remodeling Consultant

October 2017 - December 2017 (3 months)

Page 1 of 5

**United States** 

Was responsible for demolition and remodel of condos in Dallas.

LA Fitness

Sales

July 2017 - September 2017 (3 months)

**United States** 

I was responsible for putting together and implementing marketing plans.

Creating flyers and other marketing products. Heavy customer service B2B and B2C sales and marketing.

Royal Access Control Technician April 2017 - July 2017 (4 months) Mckinney, Texas

Responsible for troubleshooting of motorized gates, CCTV systems, and access control as well as installation of all of these. Performed some welding as well.

Elliott Security Solutions
Assistant Manager
February 2017 - April 2017 (3 months)
DEW

Rover / Supervisor

Elliott Security Solutions
Security Officer
January 2017 - February 2017 (2 months)
Texas Branch

Securitas Security Services USA, Inc.
Security - Badging Department
May 2015 - November 2016 (1 year 7 months)

I was responsible for managing paperwork, and filing personnel packets into our filing cabinet; as well as programming access via badges for the entire North American region of a large telecom company. I had to build spreadsheets to track who had access and help update our database of employees who left. I was also responsible for handle scheduling sometimes with other departments utilizing Outlook, Lync, and Skype. Interacted with people from all over the world on a daily basis, running the window for our

department; I was also responsible for the multi-line phone system for our department, re-routing phone calls when needed.

I learned and furthered my knowledge of several administrative type tasks. I also successfully worked across departments to schedule new employee orientation photos.

iidon Security Associates Security Officer February 2015 - May 2015 (4 months)

I was responsible for handling access to one building, 2 parking garages; and dock, with one other officers. We were responsible for checking in out visitors, cleaning personnel, and managing keys. Monitored a multi line phone system. Using spreadsheets we logged incidents and money taken in for our parking garage. We controlled lights and air for the floors as well as all gates and doors to the dock, building; and gates to garages.

I furthered my knowledge of multi line phones, and gate access control.

P2P Global Security Officer July 2014 - February 2015 (8 months)

Working with a team I was responsible for a high-rise building. We managed access to elevators, doors and turnstyles; as well as the parking garage during business hours. After hours we did floor checks and water sprinkler checks. On a second site I worked at each week, we managed a power plant. We controlled and logged all personell entering or exiting the power plant as well as logged in chemical trucks and what they are carrying. After traffic slowed down and the plants normal hours were over, we drove around the site to check on everything; confirm all gates were locked, and then lock up the management office.

I further built my documentation skills, through having to log every entry/exit and ;if it was a chemical truck, what and how much they were delivering.

St. Moritz Security Services, Inc.

Security Officer February 2014 - June 2014 (5 months)

I worked as a subcontractor along side of hotel security. I was responsible for patrolling the parking lots, a parking garage and an ajoining building. After we went around the parking lot; we were responsible for locking all exterior doors for the hotel and close up their pool. I also worked at various stores as a in store security officer; Omega, Todd's and other high end stores. I got to do event security and we covered UFC staying at the hotel. I was put in charge of supervising a car auction with three officers under me. I also had the opportunity to work security for the national volleyball championships. One other task I did was traffic control for a large event center.

I learned management skills.

Valor Security Services Security Officer February 2012 - March 2014 (2 years 2 months)

I was responsible for interior and exterior patrols with a team during the day and at night; by myself. We patrolled parking lots in vehicles bicycles and on foot, preventing thefts, and providing help with jumpstarts/lost cars. It was a very customer friendly jump we were told to talk to all customers the we can speak to without yelling and wave at the others. I built a huge confidence talking to people here and as well as managing multiple tasks at once. we had to do jobs that popped up, help customers; and still get our tasks that happen at certain times.

I learned to manage, time, tasks, and at a fast pace.

Universal Services of America Security Officer August 2012 - November 2012 (4 months) I was part of a two man team responsible for two buildings and three parking garages. We patrolled the buildings in shift by foot at night; and on golfcart out side. We had to chrck gauges in various

places around the plant as well. We were in charge of checking bades in and out for visitors and contractors; as well as key sets. We then keep track of whether they were in our out using spreadsheets.

I learned how to make an entire days plan, including lunch for two officers; loosely enough for an event or call.

ICI

Technician 2008 - 2012 (5 years)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Worked during the summers and then some after graduating in 2009; installing access control systems. I have experience with strikes, mag locks, readers, motion detectors, HID and MiFare( cards programs, and systems,) cameras, and glass breaks.

### Education

Southern Methodist University
Certificate, Code Camp (2019 - 2019)

ATI Career Training Center-Dallas

Electronic Systems Technician Certification, Industrial Electronics Technology/ Technician · (2010 - 2010)